<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ocr on Mozilla A11y</title>
    <link>https://hamletv.github.io/tags/ocr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ocr on Mozilla A11y</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hamletv.github.io/tags/ocr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Image A11y: proof of concept</title>
      <link>https://hamletv.github.io/post/image-a11y-proof-of-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hamletv.github.io/post/image-a11y-proof-of-concept/</guid>
      <description>Running the Code The gif above is tesseract.js at work. It is scanning an image available online and it outputs text into a new div, for my purposes it will be an invisible paragraph tag. This gif is from the port&amp;rsquo;s repo on Github and that is what I need to accomplish and have it perform in any page the extension is activated on. The project is as I&amp;rsquo;ve said to myself and to others, not overly challenging&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m sure I will come to regret spreading that inaccuracy (I already do, hence the title of the next section).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image A11y: background, tesseract.js and scope</title>
      <link>https://hamletv.github.io/post/ocr-with-tesseract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hamletv.github.io/post/ocr-with-tesseract/</guid>
      <description>Origins of Image A11y Simply put, the object of the Image A11y project is to improve web accessibility by making the content (specifically text) within images accessible to screen readers. The idea of Image A11y came about during the December 2016 Mozilla All Hands conference in Austin, TX. While giving a demo of an accessibility project I had worked on to the Mozilla accessibility team I was introduced to Project Naptha.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>